LoveEcho!字幕组倾情制作
本视频和字幕仅供个人学习交流使用,请于下载后24小时内删除；如需收藏请支持正版。
因私自传播造成的一切后果以及法律责任,LoveEcho!概不负责。
Honoka-chan!
穗乃果
It's cold!
好凉
Honoka-chan!
穗乃果
Why?
为什么
Why? Why? Why?
为什么为什么为什么
It's impossible! Let's go home!
果然有些勉强呢 回家吧
It's okay! I can do it this time!
没关系 下次的话一定可以成功
Ready?
要上了
I, Honaka Kosaka am a second year at Otonokizaka High!
我是高坂穗乃果 就读于音乃木坂学院高中二年级
Today, we are sending off the third years for their graduation!
今天是三年级的毕业典礼
Well, at least we were supposed to…
虽然原本应该是那样的
wu--
呜哇
Hanayo-chan!
花阳
It seems like there's sudden news…
不知怎么 突然来了通知
It's a dome…
巨蛋
What?
哎
Doo...
巨
It's a doom!
是巨蛋
"D-doom"?
巨蛋
Honaka!
穗乃果
Hnoka-chan!
It's a dome competition!
是巨蛋大会
A dome competition?!
巨蛋大会
The Akiba Dome!
是秋叶原巨蛋
The third Love Live might be held at the Akiba Dome!
第三回LoveLive大赛正在商讨于秋叶原巨蛋进行开展
Is Akiba Dome the one where they play baseball?
你说的秋叶原巨蛋 就是一直在举行棒球比赛的那个吗
In that big stadium?
在那么大的会场
We can appear on stage?!
我们能出演吗
No, no! We already graduated!
不可能啦 我们不是已经毕业了嘛
Until the end of the month, we're still school idols, right?!
到这个月底依旧还是校园偶像的吧
I knew you would all be here
果然在这里呢
Huh?
嗯
Mama…
妈妈
Director…
理事长
By those looks on your faces, I'm guessing you already heard about the next Love Live!
看你们的神情好像已经听说了呢 关于下一届LoveLive的事情
Y-Yeah! Are they really going to do it?
啊是的 真的要举行吗
At the dome?
在巨蛋
It hasn't been confirmed yet
尚且还未确定下来
To make it happen, they wanted some help from you all, the previous champions
因此 为了实现这事 希望作为上次优胜者的你们能够进行协助
I was just notified.
刚刚来了这样的联络通知呢
That couldn't mean…
那个 难道是
It can't be!
难道是
Kotori, do you have your passport? What about your plane ticket?!
小鸟 护照没事吧 机票呢
Don't worry about it!
没事啦
Thanks, Papa!
谢谢你 爸爸
I'll be going now.
我出发了
Okay! Here we go!
好啦 那么要拍了哦
Everyone, smile now!
大家都面带微笑
Ready?
预备
Nico-Nico-Ni!
妮可妮可妮
Here!
给
It's an amulet!
这个是护身符
There are enough for everybody.
大家的份也有的哟
Thank you.
谢谢
By the way, where's Honoka?
话说穗乃果呢
Wow!
好厉害喵
Rin-chan, let's go back to the group…
凛 我们回到大伙那儿去吧
I'm so pumped up!
情绪高涨起来了呢喵
Let's go look around. Kayo-chin!
花阳亲 四处转转去吧
S-Someone help me!
谁 谁来救救我呀
It's the perfect card for a journey.
对于旅途而言最棒的卡呢
Honoka-chan isn't here.
穗乃果不在哟
Don't tell me…
难道说
No, she said she's already here.
没 她说已经到了
Honoka!
穗乃果
We're really going, aren't we?
我们要出发了呢
To that sky…
向着那片蓝天
To a world we've never seen before!
向着从未见识过的世界
Next person,please
下一位
Huh, yeah
啊 好
Y-Yes
Hey, Hanayo, your bag!
啊等等花阳 行李箱
Eli!
绘里
Huh?
哦
I-Is this really okay?
没 没关系的吧
It's fine.
没事啦
Just give that note to the driver.
那个便签交给司机就好
But…
可是
Umi-chan! The people behind us are waiting!
海未 下一个人还在等着呢
-Let's get a move on!   -Wait...
-上车了喵     -稍等一下
Is this really okay?!
真的没事吗
He won't take us to some weird place, will he?
不会被拐带去了什么奇怪的地方对吧
You don't need to worry if it's a reputable taxi.
正规的出租车的话不必担心的
Nozomi-chan and Eli-chan said so.
希和绘里也有这么说过的
But we can't understand each other!
但是 语言互相不通的啊
Why are we going overseas in the first place?
话说回来为什么是海外呢
If it's a concert, can't we just do it in Japan?
Live的话在日本就可以的吧
Remember what my mom said?
我妈妈有说过的不是嘛
A TV station over here wanted to do a report on school idols,
说是由于这边的电视台想要介绍校园偶像
So they gave Otonokizaka High the offer.
就邀请了音乃木坂学院
Pretty cool, huh?!
真是件了不起的事情呢
The Akiba Dome can hold ten times the people the second competition did.
秋叶原巨蛋的收容人数是第二回决胜会场的大约10倍
Ten times?!
10倍
It's that big...?
有那么大的啊
Although Love Live's popularity has been skyrocketing,
虽然据说LoveLive的人气有强劲的势头
It will be very difficult to sell out the dome with the way things are right now
但仅仅光凭现在的实绩要确保这个会场还是很困难的
So by doing this live broadcast, we can gain exposure…
因此通过这个转播 更进一步宣传造势一下
And try to make this dome competition actually happen!
也就是说要创作出能实现巨蛋大会的实绩呢
And if it does actually happen,μ's will be invited, right?
如果实现了的话 μ's会作为嘉宾被邀请出席的对吧
I don't know. We probably will.
虽然并不知道 大概会是那样的不是么
It has to be definitely, not probably!
不是什么大概是一定
Millions of people will be crowding into the dome for Nico!
为了妮可 前来汇集于巨蛋的数以万计的观众
Won! Der! Ful!
啊太棒了
Gross.
真让人不舒服
What?!
你说啥
Wow!
好厉害
That's a lot of buildings!
好多的高层大厦
I'll say!
真的呢
That bridge! I've seen it in a book!
那座桥 在书上有读到过呢
Wow! This kind of city exists in the world!
这样的城市在世上也是存在的啊
It's amazing!
好厉害呢
Oh, look, look!
啊快看快看
What a big truck!
好大的卡车
What a big hotel!
好大的宾馆
What a big lobby!
好大的前厅
Gorgeous!
好豪华
Once Umi and the others get here, that will be all of us.
这样的话海未她们来了就全员到齐了呢
Did you tell them the right place?
有好好地告诉地点吗
Don't worry about it.
安心啦
Honaka gave them the note.
毕竟有穗乃果交给的便签
Yeah, yeah.
嗯嗯
This… is a hotel?
这个 就是宾馆 吗
Something seems… off…
好像哪里打开方式不太对似的
It's like a haunted house…
好像鬼屋一般呢喵
This isn't the right hotel at all!!!!
哦啊和听说的名字不一样
Sorry!
对不起
I copied the name wrong from the note Eli-chan gave me!
绘里给我的便签 我抄错了
You know, it was in English
因为 毕竟是英语嘛
I won't let this slide! Not today!
不管你说什么 今天绝不会原谅你的
Do you not realize how much trouble you're causing
你那个满嘴闲话粗枝大叶什么也不在乎的性格
With your sloppy and careless personality?!
到底给我们惹来了多少的麻烦和困难你到底明白吗
Hey, at least you made it.
好啦 反正也好好地到达了
That's only because Rin remembered the hotel name!
那是因为凛有好好地记得宾馆的名字好吧
If she had forgotten it, we wouldn't be alive right now!
如果忘记了的话 现在这会已经生命不保了呀
You're overreacting…
小题大做呢喵
Umi-chan, do you wanna go look at all our rooms?
海未 不去看一下大家的房间吗
The hotel lobby was amazing, too.
宾馆的大厅也很厉害的哟
How about going to a nearby cafe?
那么 就近的咖啡店
Hey, how about recharge a little with some snacks?
那个 吃点甜点转换心情怎么样
I bought cupcakes!
我买了杯形蛋糕
Oh! Nice, Hanayo-chan!
哇哦花阳太赞了
Then, after eating we'll go over our schedule for tomorrow.
那么 吃完那个之后 来决定明天以后的日程吧
Yeah! You'll eat some too, right Umi-chan?
嗯海未也要吃的对吧
I'll have some.
那我不客气了
I want to go to that building that looks like a pencil!
我想去爬那个像铅笔一样的大厦
What do you think we came here for?
你觉得到这里来是干什么来的
What was it again?
是什么来着
For the concert!
是Live
I know.
我知道的啦
We have a very important concert!
有很重要的Live呢
We don't have time to be touring.
没有什么观光的闲暇时间
Aww! But…
诶可是
Fortunately, the hotel has a dance studio in the gym.
幸运的是 宾馆里面的健身房同时有配备音响设备
Let's practice there!
我们在那里练习吧
And not go outside!
不外出
What?
诶
When we came all this way?
明明专门跑来了
Being lost must have sacred you…
看来是吓得不轻啊
It's okay, it's okay!
没关系没关系
The people in this city looked so nice--
城市里的人们 大家好像都很和善的样子
I can't trust anything you say, Honoka.
穗乃果说的话一概不相信
As winners of Love Live, we absolutely cannot stack during this live broadcast.
确实 即使作为LoveLive的优胜者 也不能对这次转播掉以轻心
Exactly my point!
就是那样的
Anyway, regarding what and where we sing, they told us we could request.
不过 有被告知"关于歌曲和场所希望我们能提出些期望"
Which place in the city fits μ's best?
在这个城市中的哪里唱歌能够看上去有μ's的风格
I think it is necessary for us to tour the city and think about it.
在城市里四处走走进行考察的必要还是有的
What? No, that's...
额 不 那个
That's right! That's right!
就是呀就是呀
Which is why we need to wake up early in the morning for practice.
因此 早上早点起来进行练习
Then, we look for the place where we want to sing, sound good?
在那之后 出行去寻找想要歌唱的地方怎么样
That sounds good to me!
我觉得那样很不错哦
Kotori!
小鸟
Who's on board?
赞成的人
Then it is decided.
决定了呢
All rightly! since it's decided, let's eat!
好差不多定下来了的话 就开始吃饭吧
Yeah!
好
Here it is!
这是您点的单
What is this?!
这是什么
It's huge!
好大
It's a cheesecake!
是乳酪蛋糕哟
I've always wanted to try this! I was so excited for it!
来到这边的话就能吃到了 之前一直在期待着呢
This is for dinner?!
这个算是晚饭吗
As expected from the land of the free…
不愧是自由的国度呢
What does that have to do with anything?
那个有什么关联性么
I will win this time!
下次一定可以赢
This one?
抽这边的吗
No, I think…
果然
H-Hey, we need to get up early tomorrow, so why don't we go to sle--
呐 由于明天要早起 差不多睡觉吧
Never!
不行
There has to be a way to win!
一定有什么能够赢的方法
Now bring it!
来吧
I'm sorry!
对不起
How could this be?!
为什么哇
I'm back.
我回来了
Maki-chan.
真姬
I got us some juice.
我买了果汁来哟
Th-Thanks.
哦 谢谢
Is this …
这个是
Why are you looking at that?
你在随便乱看什么呢
Sorry.
抱歉
Did you…look inside?
里面 你看见了吗
Yeah.
嗯
Maki-chan, did you…
真姬 难道说
It's fine.
好了
I'm doing it on my own.
由于是我擅自私下做的
So don't worry about it.
请别在意
It's so beautiful…
真漂亮呢
Yeah.
嗯
What's wrong?
哦怎么了呢
I was just thinking…
总觉得
To be in a place you don't know at all…
有种在完全不熟悉的地方
It's such a mysterious feeling.
真是不可思议的心情啊这样的感觉
We're come really far.
来到了很远的地方呢
Kayo-chin…
花阳亲
Are you sad?
寂寞了吗
Yeah…
嗯
A little bit.
稍稍有一点
You're so warm…
好温暖
One more time!
再来一次
What?!
咦
There has to be something…
肯定有什么
There has to be something!
肯定有什么原因
I'm not cheating!
没有在耍花招啊
Then let's go one more time!
那样的话 就再来一次
Honoka-chan!
穗乃果
What…? Heavy… It's heavy…
呃呃呃 什么 好重 好重啊
What is this?
这是什么鬼
Hey, Honoka!
我说穗乃果
Why are you at my house, Nico-chan?
为什么妮可会在我家啊
Because it's not your house!
因为这不是你家啊
Your sleeping habits are just awful! Seriously!
你这是多差劲的睡相啊真是的
This bed is all wrong! This is the honeymoon suite!
又是搞错了床铺 这个还弄成了蜜月样式的
What's up with that?!
你到底是有什么企图
What do you want from me…?
你就算和我说这个
You should say something too, Eli!
绘里也多少说句啊
Grandmother…
奶奶
She said "Grandmother"…
I never really realized this, but …
直到现在虽然没有察觉到
I guess Eli-chan can be quite the spoiled child.
绘里说不定意外地爱粘人呢
Grandmother…
奶奶
The morning feels so good!
早上真舒服呢
I'm getting hyped up!
兴致大涨了喵
Okay! Let's go!
那么出发吧
To have such a huge park in the middle of a big city is amazing!
在大都市的正中间能有这么大的公园之类的 真是太棒了
How long are you girls going to talk?
真是的 要一直聊到什么时候啊
Umi-chan! It's okay!
海未没事的哟
I can …trust you, right?
相信你是可以的对吧
We're off!
出发了喵
Meow, meow, meow, meow!
喵喵喵喵
Rin-chan sure has a lot of energy.
凛真是充满活力呢
Hello!
你好
What?! Um…
哎啊
H-Hello…
你好
Wow! Look! There's a stage here!
啊快看 在这种地方有舞台
You're right.
真的哎
I wonder if they do concerts here…
不知道有没有在举办音乐会之类的
Do you want to get on it?
要不要稍微登上去试一试
I'm so tired!
好累啊
If feels so good.
好舒服
It's not a bad idea to have the concert here, either.
Live把这里作为舞台说不定也并不算坏呢
It's really calming.
总感觉能够平静下心来
It's probably calming because we're all together.
能静下心不是应该由于是和大家在一起吗
Maybe.
说不定是那样呢
Hey.
呐
Wanna dance a little bit?
要不要稍微是这跳一下
Rin-chan!
凛
Ready?
可以吗
I'll be the leader!
与其说可以不如说交给我吧喵
Hello!
哈喽
Are you girls Japanese?
你们是日本人吗
Y-Yes!
是是的
We are Japanese student.
我们是日本学生
You're here for some performance?
你们是来这里进行表演的吗
Wh-What is she saying?
她在说什么呢
It doesn't seem like she's upset…
总觉得貌似并没有在生气
Even I understand that…
那个就算是我也明白的
Yes, we are school idols!
是的 我们是校园偶像
We are called μ's!
我们叫μ's
School idols?
校园偶像
Well Japan seems cool!
啊哈哈 好吧 日本看起来很酷啊
We'd wanna go there too!
我们也想去那
Well, I hope you have a fun time around here!
那么 希望你们能在这里有段美好的时光
Enjoy your stay! Bye!
玩的开心拜拜
Bye!
拜拜
See you!
再见
They said since we came all the way here, we should look around.
"由于好不容易来一回 请到处参观一下"
Well?
她们如是说
如是说
You're amazing, Nozomi-chan!
希好厉害
She did go to the South Pole.
果然不愧是有去过南极的呢
Overseas isn't so bad, right?
海外也没那么坏对吧
Of course, you still need to be cautious.
当然多加注意虽然是必要的
I guess you're  right…
说不定是那样的
All right!
好
After a good practice,  let's go see this city!
那么 好好做练习之后我们去参观这个城市吧
Wow!
哇哦哦哦
You can see it now!
渐渐能看到了呐
It's so big.
好大呢喵
Take it, take it!
照张照张
Honoka-chan, you sort of look a hero!
总觉得穗乃果 像英雄一样
All right, I'm gonna take it!
那么 我拍了哟
O-Okay.
好 好的
Can we eat all of this ?!
这些 全部能吃掉么
I'm so happy!
啊 好幸福
Here you are.
来给你
Thank you!
谢谢
You're welcome!
不客气
This is the main street.
这里就是主街道哟
You eat breakfast at a restaurant called Tiffany's, right?
哎在名叫蒂凡尼之类的店吃早餐吧怎么样
-I wonder what kind of restaurant it is!
-Yeah, yeah!
-不知是家多么棒的餐厅呐
-嗯 嗯
Do you know, Nico-chan?
妮可你知道吗
Wha-? O-Of course!
诶理 理所当然的不是吗
Seriously?
真的吗
What are they going to serve us?
会让我吃什么呢
S-Steaks?
牛 牛排之类
Awesome!
好棒啊喵
All of that is wrong!
全部都错了
Got a good picture!
很好地拍下来了哟
Wow!
哇哦
Yeah! You're both so cute!
嗯两人都很可爱
Unique clothes!
与众不同的服装呢
These clothes are embarrassing!
如此令人害羞的服装
Khorosho!
Хорошо
As expected from the person in charge of the costumes for μ's.
真不愧是μ's的服装担当呢
Both of you look good!
你们二人都很合身哟
R-Really?
是 是吗
You look cute, too, Umi-chan!
海未也很可爱
R-Really?
是 是那样的吗
What's that?
那是什么
During Halloween, people do it as a dare.
据说是万圣节的时候呢 城市里的人们恶作剧弄成的
Should we give it a try?
我们也尝试一下吗
Can we?
可以吗
just leave it to me!
哎嘿嘿 交给我好了
Hey! My shoes!!
啊等等 我的鞋子
It's called the center of the world for a reason.
不愧是世界的中心
It's beautiful, isn't it?
好漂亮呢
If only we could use this kind of scenery during our concert…
Live的时候 要是能用到这样的景色
That would be the best.
就再好不过了
All the places seem good.
唉 总觉得哪里都是好地方
It's so hard to decide!
有点迷茫呢
Yeah.
是的呢
Initially, I was worried if we would be able to perform our best overseas.
刚开始有担心过在陌生的地方能不能办成富有我们自己风格的Live
Right…
这样啊
What's wrong?
怎么了呢
I got it! I got it now!
我知道了我知道了呢
I know why we're so excited to be in this city!
这个城市十分令人心潮澎湃的原因
This city is sort of similar to Akiba!
这个城市呢 稍微有点和秋叶原相似的哟
This city?
这个城市
To Akiba?
和秋叶原
Yes!
嗯
It's filled with so many fun things!
充满着很多愉快的事物
It's constantly changing!
连续不断地更新进化着
I actually feel the same way, just a little bit!
实际上我也稍微有些感觉到了
You were too, huh?
凛你说是那样的吧
Yup!
嗯
Now that you mention it, you might be right.
一语道破之后再看看说不定就是那样的呢
Always taking in new things and evolving…
不管什么都兼容并收 不断地变化着
That's why no matter the venue, we thought we could perform a true μ's concert.
因此我觉得不管在什么地方 似乎都能举办成有着μ's风格的Live呐
It's raining…
下雨了
I don't have an umbrella…
哎没有雨伞哦
Well, this is a problem.
有点伤脑筋了呢
But there are still places I want to see…
哎 明明尚且还有很多想去的地方
There's nothing we can do about it.
没办法了呢
It might start raining harder…
而且雨说不定会变得更大
Yeah…
嗯
It's better if we go back to the hotel.
回宾馆去会比较好的样子呢
How sad…
好凄寂啊
Everything will be fine!
哎嘿嘿 没关系的喵
Hello,歌に呼ばれて
Hello,被歌曲呼唤而来
光あふれる街はカーニバルみたい
充满光的街道就像嘉年华一样
Hello,応えてみたら
Hello,试着回应下
きっと一歩ずつ世界ひろがるよ Hello!
世界一定会一步一步的变的更加宽广的Hello!
踊りだす交差点で みんな驚かない
在十字路口跳起舞来大家都不会惊讶
なにもかも自由なの?
不管做什么都是自由的吗
流れるひとの波に
好像要被流逝着的
飲み込まれそうになるよ
被人群的波涛吞噬了的感觉
知らない言葉のメロディー
随着不明白的言语的旋律里
不思議と力が 湧いてくる
涌出了不可思议的力量
Hello,星を数えて
Hello,来数数星星
これから出会うことを占えば
来预测下这之后的相会
Hello,予測不可能!?
Hello,没办法预测!?
きっと一緒なら全部楽しめる Hello!
一定是大家一起就能享受全部Hello!
明日起きたら どうなるかな
明日起来后会变成怎样呢
どうしようかな
要怎么办才好呢
It's starlit sky!
是星空呢喵
Is Hanayo-chan…crying?
花阳 在哭
What happened?
怎么了呐
Nico-chan! Did you do something to Kayo-chin?
妮可 你对花阳做了什么吗
I don't know!
我才不知道呢
What's wrong? Are you not feeling well?
怎么了呢不舒服吗
Homesick?
思乡了
Ice…
发
"Ice"?
Why ice…?
发
I want to eat white rice!
我想吃白饭
White rice?
白饭
Yes! Ever since we came here…
是自从来到了这边
Breakfast, lunch, dinner, it's bread, bread, bread, bread, bread!
上午也好中午也好晚上也好全都是面包面包面包面包面包
There's no white rice!
完全没有白米啊
But we added some rice to yesterday's meal—
但是昨天的有配菜有饭
White rice is not an "addition"
白米不是配菜
It's a staple food!
是主食
And that was saffron rice, which isn't the same!
和干巴巴的红花饭是似是而非的东西
Every good dish starts with rice.
写作饣和反读作饭
It's because of rice that we can even call it a meal!
首先有了白米 就有了饭
I want to eat white rice in a warm rice bowl...
想用暖和的茶碗吃白白的饭
Oh, this bread is yummy!
啊 这面包真好吃
You're a real white rice fanatic...
对白米的执着真是厉害
But that really can't be helped...
但就算你这么说
Maki-chan, do you know any good places?
真姬 你知道什么好地方吗
Well, I might know a place...
嘛 也不是不知道啦
I can't believe this city had this kind of restaurant.
没想到这个城市也会有这种地方呢
It is the center of the world.
因为是世界的中心啊
You can find almost anything here.
东西大抵都有哦
It was so good...
好好吃啊
White rice is the best!
果然白米最棒了
Satisfied, Kayo-chin?
太好了呢 花阳亲
All right, let's go back before it gets too late.
那么 在变晚前快回去吧
Sure!
嗯
It feels like we're walking back from school.
总觉得这样像是放学回家一样啊
That's true.
是啊
It's an odd feeling.
奇妙的感觉
像这样和大家在一起的时间
Although we don't have much time left together...
明明已经不多了
This city helps us forget that somehow.
这座城市却不可思议的让我们忘记这件事
Huh? Huh?
咦
Sorry.
对不起
Oh, EXCUSE ME.
噢 借过一下
Maybe I don't have enough money...
钱不够了吗
And then, you taught me...
然后呢 叫你教我的
Hey!
啊 等一下
啊
等
EXCUSE ME!
抱歉打扰一下
Ouch!
好疼
Ow!
Owie!
好疼啊
Did I ... get separated?
难道说 走散了
What do I do?!
怎么办啊
The station at the hotel didn't have stairs like this, did it?
宾馆那边的车站好像不是这样的楼梯吧
Oh, sorr—
打扰一下
Sorry.
抱歉
这些事情亘久不变
The fundamental things apply
What station did I get on?
是从哪个站过来的来着
As time goes by
即使时光荏苒
And when two lovers woo
当恋人甜言蜜语之时
They still say, "I love you"
他们依旧说「我爱你」
On that you can rely
而那是你可依靠的
No matter what the future brings
无须担心将来会带来什么
As time goes by
即使时光荏苒
Moonlight and love songs
月光与情歌
Never out of date
永不会过时
Hearts full of passion
热情与嫉恨
Jealousy and hate
充满于心中
Woman needs man
她需要他
And man must have his mate
而他也要有伴侣
That no one can deny
这无人可否认
Well, It's still the same old story
古老故事情节仍在重复
A fight for love and glory
一场为了爱与荣誉的战斗
A case of do or die
去做或是死亡的情节
The world will always welcome lovers
这个世界将永远欢迎有情的恋人们
As time goes by
即使时光荏苒
Thank you!
谢谢
Everyone thanks a lot for being here today.
谢谢大家今天捧场
希望你们都能喜欢我的表演
I would love to see you all at my live performance, too!
Bye!
拜
Well, there are some girl who easily get lost...
偶尔也会有啦
像你一样迷路的人
But to think you don't even know the name of the hotel!
但没想到你连宾馆的名字也不知道
Sorry...
真抱歉
But Miss, I'm surprised you guessed it just from me saying it was a big station!
但是姐姐你居然只凭一句很大的车站就能知道
Huh?
诶
All of your gestures are so exaggerated!
你的每个动作都好夸张啊
Don't worry. I sort of know where it is.
没问题啦 大致的地方我知道啦
It's a big hotel near a big station, right?
有很大车站的地方的很大的宾馆对吧
Yes!
是的
There's also a huge chandelier, right?
还有很大的吊灯对吧
There is!
有的
Then, it's got to be that place!
那毫无疑问就是那里呢
What's wrong?
怎么了吗
I forgot my mic!
把麦克风忘记了
Um...
那什么
Could it be that...?
难不成是 那个吧
Oops!
啊
Don't scare me like that!
请不要吓人家啊
Sorry! Sorry!
抱歉抱歉
At least I found it!
有了就好了啊
Have you been singing here for a while now?
您一直都在这边唱歌吗
Something like that.
算是吧
I know I don't look it,
别看我现在这样
but I used to sing with a group back then.
我以前还是和朋友一起唱的
In Japan.
在日本哦
Oh, really?!
是这样吗
Yup!
嗯
But... a lot of things happened...
但是 发生了很多
In the end, we had to split up.
组合也解散了
At the time, I didn't know what to do...
当时也不知道到底该怎么办
I just thought it might be a good opportunity to move on,
这会是迈向下一步的好机会吗
take the next step.
曾经也想过这样的事啊
What's wrong?
怎么了
And then...
那么
And then what happened?
那么在那之后呢
It was easy!
很简单哦
It was very easy.
非常的简单
The reason why we sang until then...
至今为止自己到底为了什么而歌唱
What we wanted to be, what we liked...
想成为什么 喜欢干什么
Thinking about all that, the answer was easy
好好想一下 答案就非常简单了
Um, I sort of get it... but not really.
那个 好像明白了又好像不明白啊
That's fine for now.
现在这样就好了
What?!
诶
It's fine like that!
这样就好
It is?!
不好啊
It's fine!
就好
What?!
诶
You'll understand soon.
马上就能明白的
Honoka!
穗乃果
Girls...
大家
Girls!
What were you thinking?!
你到底干什么去了
Umi-chan...
海未
Do you know how hard we looked for you?
你知道我们找了你多久了吗
Sorry
对不起
Oh, right. Before I got here...
对了 其实我到这为止
Huh?
咦
I met a woman who led me here...
是和中途遇到的人一起来的
A woman?
人
Nobody's there...
谁都不在啊
No, really!
怎么会
It doesn't matter now.
算了
Let's hurry back to our rooms and prepare for tomorrow.
赶快回房间为明天做准备吧
Oh, Honoka-chan, welcome back!
啊 穗乃果回来了
I'm so glad!
太好了
You're late!
太慢了
Hey, girls!
呐 大家
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm supposed to be the leader, but I made you all worry...
我明明是领队却让大家担心了
It's fine already.
已经没事了
To make up for it...
不过
You're going to lead tomorrow's performance, and make it a good one.
明天就由你来带领大家做出最棒的演出吧
Eli-chan...
绘里
This is our last stage.
这可是我们最后的表演
I won't forgive you if you slack off for even a second!
稍微放下水都不饶你哦
Yeah.
嗯
Then, let's go to sleep for tomorrow!
那么向着明天睡觉吧喵
Why are you going to put so much spirit into going to sleep?
你睡觉打气是要干嘛啊
The reason why we sing...
为了什么而歌唱吗
ココはどこ?
这里是哪里?
待って言わないで わかってる
等等不要说 我明白的
夢に見た熱い蜃気楼なのさ
那是在梦里见到的炽热的海市蜃楼
キミはだれ?
你是谁?
なんて訊かないよ わかってる
不会问这个问题 因为我很清楚
おたがいの願いが呼んだ出会い
因为被相互呼唤着的愿望聚集到了一起
遠ざかるほど光る一番星
愈远愈闪耀的最亮的星星
いつかそんな恋してみたかった
曾经也想过来一场如此的恋爱
もういらないよ胸のブレーキは
已经不再需要了的心中的刹车
見つめあうために生まれた二人になってく
因为成为了为了注视着对方而诞生的两个人
Ah! 「もしも」は欲しくないのさ
Ah!我想要的不是「如果」
「もっと」が好きAngel
喜欢「更多」的Angel
翼をただの飾りにはしない
不会将羽翼作为单纯的装饰品
Ah! 「もしも」は欲しくないけど
Ah!虽然不想要「如果」
「もっと」は好きAngel
但是喜欢「更多」的Angel
明日じゃない
不是在明日
大事なときは今なんだと気がついて
而是会注意到更加重要的是当下
こころの羽ばたきは止まらない
无法停止的振翅的心灵
It's beautiful...
好漂亮
Honoka-chan...
穗乃果
Look...
快看
Were you awake the whole time?
你一直醒着吗
Nope, I just woke up.
不 刚刚起来
Hey, Kotori-chan
呐 小鸟
The concert was fun, huh?
表演 真开心啊
Yeah!
嗯
We were able to make a lot of memories with everyone.
和大家留下了很多回忆
Let's all go again someday.
之后有机会再去吧
Yeah. Let's al go together again.
嗯 大家再去一次吧
Someday... Definitely...
总有一天 一定
Hey! Hey! It seems like yesterday's broadcast got a lot of buzz!
呐呐 昨天的转播很受好评的样子
I'm so glad!
太好了喵
Hopefully we'll be in top form like this for the dome competition.
巨蛋大会如果也能像这样实现就好了啊
Yeah!
嗯
I guess I'm just not used to flying coach...
经济舱的来回也就这种感觉啊
You braggin'?!
你在炫耀吗
No, it's not that!
不是啦
Hmph!
哼
I see you're both still energetic.
两位才刚回来就这么精神啊
I'm not!
才不精神啦
By the way, Maki-chan
说起来真姬
Did you finish the song?
曲子做好了吗
Wha-?
什
I told you, it doesn't matter!
所以说那个是没关系的
I think it's a good song.
咱觉得是首好曲子哦
I'm telling you, it's not!
所以说不是啊
Looks like the bus is coming.
巴士差不多要来了哦
Go!
走吧
Yeah! Let's go home, then!
嗯 那么回去吧
Do you know them?
是认识的人吗
No
不
They're really cute!
果然好可爱
They looked this way!
刚才看这边了
What?!
什么情况
This is
这是
What's going on?
怎么回事
They're staring at us
大家都在看这边
Could it be a sniper?!
难道是狙击手
What?!
诶
What did you do?! Did you sneak something past customs?!
你做了什么 从那边顺了点东西回来吗
I don't know!
我才不知道啊
U-Um...
那 那个
Please give me your autograph!
请帮我签名
Um...
那个
You're Honoka Kasoka-san from μ's, right?
你是μ's的高坂穗乃果吧
Um, yes!
是 是的
You must be Kotori Minami-san, right?
那边的是南小鸟对吧
Yes.
是啊
And you must be Umi Sonoda-san, right?
那边是园田海未吧
You're mistaken.
你认错了
Umi-chan!
海未
Why are you lying?!
为什么要说谎
Because it's scary!
因为 不是很可怕吗
At the airport all of a sudden...
在机场突然这样
I'm the biggest fan of μ's!
我是μ's的大粉丝
Fan...?
粉丝
Me, too!
我也是
I love you guys, too!
我也超喜欢
Please!
拜托了
What's going on...?
这到底是
I don't know...
不知道啊
Oh! Maybe it's a dream!
难道这是梦
That could be a possibility!
这有可能喵
If that's the case, then when exactly did the dream start?
但如果是的话 从哪里开始是梦
Before we went on the trip?
那个 从去旅行前开始
What?! From all the way back then?!
诶 从这么前面就是吗
That's pushing is...
这个再怎么说也
Or maybe...
还是说
From when our school was going to shut down?! From back then?!
难道从"学校要废校!"的附近开始
That's a long dream!
好长的梦喵
There's no way that can be true!
怎么可能有这种事
Right? Umi-chan?
是吧 海未
Then, why?
那为什么
大家一起
为她们加油吧
This is ....
这是
What...?
到底
Is going on?!
怎么回事
Meow!
喵
-It's over here, too!   -There are fliers, too!
-这边也有喵    -这种应援传单也有
What is this ...?
这是
Um,
那个
could you be...?
难道
μ's?!
μ's
it's true!
真的欸
Wow! It really is them!
好厉害是真人
Wow! Amazing!
哇 好厉害
I'm a huge fan!
我是你们的粉丝
Th-Thank you.
啊 谢谢你
Well, isn't this just great?
真头疼啊
Umi-chan...
海未
Impossible! I can't do this!
办不到 这样的绝对办不到
Ever since we got back, we've been getting a lot of attention just walking around the city.
从回来之后就有随便在街上走走就会被认出来的注目度
The overseas performance is playing all over Akiba
秋叶原中到处都放着海外的表演
Maybe, it really is a dream...
果然这是梦吧
Honoka-chan!
穗乃果
But, I get why you think that.
但是这样认为也能够理解
The view counts are crazy!
好厉害的观看数
Then we... really did become famous?
那我们真的变成了名人
No way!
怎么这样
I can't! It's embarrassing!
我做不到 好丢人
But, you know what...?
但是这就是说
That means the overseas performance was a huge success, right?!
海外的演出非常成功的意思对吧
Yup! I think so!
嗯 是这样吧
Going to the dome won't be just a dream, right?!
去巨蛋也不是梦想了对吧
If the dome competition happens,
如果巨蛋大会能实现的话
then Love Live will stay popular!
LoveLive就能一直一直持续下去了吧
I'm so glad! I'm so happy!
太好了 好开心
It's too early to say.
说这些还太早了
For now, we should focus on retreating without being caught.
比起这个 还是先不被暴露的离开这里吧
That's right. Because as of now...
是啊 因为我们
We are stars!
现在是明星啊
ランナウェイだ ランランナウェイだ
逃跑逃跑快逃跑呀
なんなんなんで突然?
为什么为什么那么突然?
ランナウェイだ ランランナウェイだ
逃跑逃跑快逃跑呀
いきなり人気者
突然就成了有名人
ああ…まさかの大ブレイク
啊…没想到会这么受欢迎
笑顔で切り抜けて ランランランナウェイ!
用笑容来突破 逃跑逃跑逃跑吧!
おかしいな もう一回目を閉じて深呼吸
真奇怪啊 再一次闭上眼深呼吸
おかしいね ホントは夢見てるのかな
真奇怪呢 其实是在做梦吧
お互いをつねろう 痛いほどつねろう
互相捏捏对方的脸 用会痛的力度来捏捏
消えないねこの街も追いかける人もね
没有消失呢这条街上追赶的人也是
消えない…消えないっ
没有消失…没有消失
ありがとうって思うヒマがないほど
连想着感谢大家的时间都没有的程度
ハテナハートビート
びっくりしたままで ?←HEARTBEAT
就这样惊讶着 ?←HEARTBEAT
幸せは突然すぎるときっと
在来的太突然的幸福中一定
ハテナから先へとなかなか進めない
无法在惊讶的感情中理解情况
さあ、どうしよう?
那么、怎么办呢?
これからさあ、どうしよう?
这之后要怎么办?
Yeah!
就是这样啊
That broadcast was getting so much buzz,
那场演出转播的评价好像真的很厉害
It got picked up by tons of places.
好像在各处都被提及到哦
Look!
你们看
You're right!
啊 真的
It's not only being shown in Akiba, it's everywhere!
不只是在秋叶原 在各处都有
It was a real pain, you know!
真的很不容易哦
So many people were asking for you when you were away.
在你们回来之前一直在问姐姐的事
Oh, welcome!
啊啦 欢迎
Uh, um...
那 那个
Is H-Honoka Kosaka-san...?
请问高坂穗乃果小姐在吗
Welcome to Honoka Kosaka's home,  Homura!
欢迎来到高坂穗乃果所住的穗村
Welcome!
欢迎
Well...Mom and Dad did say they were happy about the increase in sales...
嘛 虽然老妈和老爸都因为营业额上涨非常开心就是了
Seriously?!
不是吧
I'm gonna go negotiate my allowance!
我去找他们交涉下零花钱
The sales went up because of me, right?!
多亏了我营业额上涨对吧
I only need them to increase it a little bit!
得让他们再给我涨点才行
Don't we have more important things to talk about?
是说这种事的场合吗
She's right.
是啊
We have to be careful about how we act, now that we're popular idols.
既然是人气偶像就注意下自己的行动啊
No way...
怎么这样
Can't you tell just by looking at A-RISE?
看了A-RISE就明白了吧
A popular idol must always have her pride and grace.
人气偶像就是随时有着自尊
Without ever getting flustered...
要优雅 毫不慌乱
Nico-chan, are you on vacation today?!
妮可今天是来度假的吗
Wow, so pretty!
呜哇 好漂亮
I guess it can't be helped.
真拿你们没办法
Nico-Nico-Nui
NikoNikonue
Nui-Nui-Nui-Nui...
Nue Nue Nue Nue
What are you doing?
你在干什么
A-Anyways! You never know when you're being watched!
总之 不知道别人在什么地方看着
When you go out, be careful what you wear and how you walk.
外出的时候要注意打扮和走路方式
What?!
诶
I don't think we need to be that careful...
这种事都要注意有点
I agree...
我也有点
It's too much work...
好麻烦啊
Before any of that...
在这之前
Shouldn't we be thinking about something else?!
有必须要思考的事啊
What should we be thinking about?
要思考的事
You don't know?
你不明白吗
We're gained so much popularity and attention from the fans.
我们的人气这么高 被这么多粉丝所关注哦
You're right.
说得也是
No doubt about it...
这毫无疑问会
The next concert?!
下一场演出
No, no, no!
没有没有没有
Absolutely not!
绝对没有
Please help us out!
这点请您通融下
Please!
拜托了
When I said you were my friends, a lot of people said they wanted to see you guys!
说是你们的朋友就有很多人说想看下一场演出
C'mon! isn't there something you can do?!
不能想想办法吗
Honoka! Honoka! Honoka!
穗乃果 穗乃果 穗乃果
Everybody thinks that we're going to have another concert...
大家都认为会有下一场演出啊
That's to be expected when we're this popular.
这么有人气的话也是当然的啊
μ's will break up after the competition...
μ's会在大会结束后停止活动
Now that I think about it, we never announced that publicly...
确实没有在我们之外说过啊
But!
但是
Everyone knows that Eli-chan and the others are third years!
大家都知道绘里你们是三年级生啊
You can't be a school idol after you graduate...
毕业之后就不能当校园偶像这点
That should go without saying!
不说出来也能明白啊
I suppose that to our fans,
大概对于观众来说
it doesn't really matter if we're school idols or not.
我们是不是校园偶像都没有多大的关系啊
In fact,
实际上
Even after they graduate from school, there are still people who pursue being idols.
也有校园偶像毕业之后继续偶像活动的人
Even though they can't enter Love Live.
虽然不能在LoveLive出场
There are plenty of people who plan concerts and release songs...
但也有很多人举办演唱会 发表新歌
I see...
这样啊
Then, what do you suggest we do?
那么 我们要怎么办呢
We have no choice. We have to do a concert.
只有举办演唱会了不是吗
A concert?
演出
Yes.
没错
In front of everyone...
在大家的面前在举办一次演出
We do another concert and tell them we are breaking up.
再好好的传达我们解散的事
Since we're gaining attention from our success with the broadcast.
在演出成功被瞩目的现在
I think it's the best thing we can do.
这才是最好的方法吧
And...
而且
We coincidentally have a suitable song...
正好有合适的曲子
Hey!
等下
We have a song?
有这种曲子
Nozomi!
希
It's all right!
这不也挺好吗
Actually, Maki-chan was writing a song.
实际上真姬已经做好了
A new song for μ's.
μ's的新曲子
Really?!
真的吗
But, we're ending... So why now?
但是明明要结束了 为什么
I thought the song at the competition would be the last one.
本来以为在大会唱的是最后一首曲子
But a lot of things happened, remember?
但在那之后也发生了事很多不是吗
That's why, to end things the right way, I...
所以为使自己告一段落 姑且做了一曲
But it's not like I wanted to sing it at a concert.
不过也没有打算在演出中唱的打算啦
This is....
这个
It's a good song.
是首好曲子呢
No fair! I wanna listen to it, too!
真好啊 凛也想要听
Is there a solo for me?!
有我的独唱部分吗
Listen! It's really good song!
听听看 非常好的一首曲子
Me, too! Me, too!
凛也要凛也要
Here!
给
I want to listen to it, too!
我也想要快点听听看
Oh! Eli-chi looks pumped!
哦 绘里亲也很有干劲啊
I-It's nothing like that...
也不是这样啦
Umi-chan, can you add lyrics to it?
海未 这样能作词吗
What are we... singing for?
我们是为了什么而歌唱的
Honoka-chan?
穗乃果
Sorry.
抱歉
If we have a wonderful song
如果有这么美妙的曲子的话
It would be a waste not to do it, right?!
不上太可惜了
Let's do it!
上吧
Announce we're splitting at our last concert!
为了传达「最后」的最后的演唱会
Practice will get harder!
练习可是会很辛苦的哦
We only have until the end of the month at Otonokizaka.
我们作为音乃木坂学院的一员也只能到这个月底了
Until then, we have a lot to do!
在那之前要做的事情还有很多哦
Girls.
各位
Do you have a moment?
打扰下可以吗
Mama?
妈妈
You want us to continue?
希望我们继续
A-RISE and μ's, lauded as the most popular school idols...
在学园偶像中拥有压倒性人气的μ's和A-RISE
For the dome competition to happen
要是想在巨蛋举行大会的话
Everyone thinks we'll need your influence.
大家觉得不管怎么你们的力量都是不可或缺的
Everyone...?
大家都
But, I understand why people might think that way.
但是这种想法也可以理解
With all this popularity...
人气到达了这种程度
Since the third years have graduated
三年生即将毕业
And if it becomes hard for you to stay school idols
觉得继续当学园偶像太困难的话
I don't mind if you reinvent yourselves
也可以选择以其他的形式
Regardless, in order to keep this momentum going...
姑且也为了不降低现在的这份热情
Everyone wants μ's to continue.
大家还是希望μ's能继续活动下去
No way...
这个
But...
但是
This has become quite a problem...
变得非常棘手了呢
We were just talking about our last concert.
明明都在商量最后的演唱会的事了
I'm opposed to this.
我持反对态度哦
Sure, we were able to get this far because of Love Live,
虽然以LoveLive为契机让我们走到这一步是事实
but is it necessary for us, μ's, to do it?
但是μ's需要做到这种地步吗
Yeah...You're right.
也是的呢
But, if we can make this event work.
但是如果能够引导大会举办成功的话
School idols will fly higher than ever.
学园偶像也可以走得更远
That was the reason why we went overseas...
也是因为这个才去海外的吧
Wait!
等下
We said we should end it...
不都决定了要好好地做个了结
μ's will end when the third years graduate!
μ's在三年生毕业的同时就走向终点吧
Maki's right.
正如真姬所说
If we said we were going to end it, we have to end it.
决定要结束的话就好好地结束吧
Am I wrong?
难道不是吗
Nico-cchi...
妮可亲
Are you sure?
没关系吗
If we continue, we can perform at the dome...
如果继续的话巨蛋的演出就
Of course I want to go!
我肯定是想出场的
But, we made a decision.
但是,我们不是已经决定了吗
All nine of us talked about it...
我们九人商议之后
We can't change our minds so easily.
那个时候的决心可是无法轻易改变的
You get it, don't you?
你们也是明白的吧
Nico...
妮可
If we end μ's.
要是μ's解散了
There's a possibility that the dome plan will fail...
那巨蛋大会说不定也就没有了呢
I don't want that to happen..Just because we didn't want to...
因为我们没有继续下去的缘故而变成那样的话
That's... true.
这个倒是
Honoka-chan...
穗乃果
What do you think, Honoka?
穗乃果怎么觉得呢
Honoka!
穗乃果
I'm home!
我回来了
Oh, Yukiho!
啊 雪穗
Sorry for the intrusion!
打扰了
Where's sister?
姐姐呢
Probably upstairs.
不是在上面吗
it's so hard...
好难办呢
Will people be happy with this?
大家会为此感到高兴吗
If μ's continues...?
如果μ's继续下去的话…
Sister!
姐姐
Do you have a minute?
打扰下可以吗
Yeah!
恩
Sorry for intruding.
打扰了
Alisa-chan! You didn't go back to Russia?
亚丽莎没有回俄罗斯吗
Nope!
是的
I'm going to work hard as a school idol!
接下来会作为学园偶像努力的
No time to go back now!
暂时不会回去了
I see.
这样吗
So...
然后然后
I wanted to get your advice about where our practice spot should be.
想和你商量一下在学校练习的场所
I didn't know where to do it.
我们不知道在哪儿练习比较好
I see.
这样啊
Is there a place you would recommend?
有什么推荐的场所吗
Probably the roof...
果然还是屋顶
It's spacious!
很宽阔
But you can't practice when it rains...
虽然下雨了就没法儿练了
Huh? But...the roof is where you guys...
但是屋顶不是你们在练吗
Yeah
是这样的
But if we're far enough away, we won't bother each other.
但是稍微离远点的话也不会因为声音干扰到 不用在意的
Then, I can secretly watch the two of you practicing hard every day...
这样的话就可以每天悄悄得看着努力的两位
No, no!
不行不行
We just started!
才刚刚开始呢
Sister?
姐姐
Is it not fun?
不开心吗
Huh? Fun?
诶 开心
That's right! I was talking to Alisa about it.
对啊 我和亚丽莎商量好了
To have as much fun being school idols as μ's!
我们要以不输给μ's的开心的学园偶像为目标
That's why...
所以
That's why I want μ's...to always be having fun!
所以我们希望μ's能够一直开心下去
See ya!
那我们先走了
Fun...
开心
A phone call?!
电话
Honoka-san?
穗乃果
Tsubasa-san!
翼
Long time no see!
好久不见
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
Uh, what's up with your outfit?
然后你这身穿着是怎么回事
Um... I left in a hurry, so...
因为太慌张了
Hey, do you have some time?
这会儿有时间吗
My car is waiting,
停车等着你的
Let's go for a drive.
去兜风吧
Dr-Drive?!
兜 兜风
Dancing dancing  Nonstop my dancing
How was it? Over there?
觉得那边如何
Oh!
嗯
We had a lot of fun
非常开心
and learned a lot!
也学到了很多东西
I see.
这样啊
Seems like your concert was a huge success.
演唱会好像也非常成功呢
Everyone's talking about it!
周围全都是关于你们的话题哦
No, not really...
哪有
So, where are you doing your next concert?
那么下一场演唱会准备在哪儿举行呢
Well...
这个
That looks like a worried face...
你露出的是「该怎么办」的表情呢
μ's will end when the third years graduate.
μ's的三年生毕业后就解散
We thought that was best for us.
我们之前觉得这是最妥当的做法
but...
但是
Now there are so many people following us...
现在有很多人等着我们的
To the point that we have major influence over Love Live...
甚至有了助LoveLive一臂之力的能力
You don't want to betray their expectations...
不想背叛期待吗
We have people that support us...
有给我们加油的人
People who say they want to hear our song...
有愿意听我们歌唱的人
I want to meet their expectations.
想回应这份期待
That's what we've always done.
一直都是这么过来的
So...
果然还是
Then why don't you continue...?
那么继续不就好了吗
I think we should.
想这样做
But...
但是
What's this?
这是
This is the team what will manage us from now on.
今后给我们做经纪公司的团队
Management?
经纪公司……
We decided to continue.
我们会继续下去
Once we graduate from school, even though we will not be school idols...
就算毕业了 不再是学园偶像了
The three of us want to sing together, as A-RISE.
三人也想继续作为A-RISE继续歌唱下去
Tsubasa-san...
翼
I understand how you're feeling.
我们也是理解你现在的心情的
I was lost, too.
也曾经迷茫过
Working towards Love Live, being school idols...
以LoveLive为目标 继续做学园偶像
And welcoming the end after you're successful. It's a beautiful thing!
我也觉得在做完一切后谢幕是一件非常美好的事
But, you know...
但是呢
It would be sad if it was over.
果然如果解散了的话会很寂寞呢
I want to have this time, this split second, to continue on.
想让这个时间、这个瞬间永远延续下去
And to entertain our audience
想让大家满意
And to fly on to a much bigger world!
向着更广阔的世界迈步
Since that's what we thought... We...
我们这样想着
You are free to come to your own conclusion.
得出什么结论是你的自由哦
But we will continue.
但是我们会继续下去
We want you to continue as well.
也希望你们能够继续下去
We used to fight against each other at Love Live, but from now on...
想以一起在LoveLive对决过的同伴身份
As allies...
今后也是
μ's...School idol...
μ's 学园偶像
I want μ's to continue...
希望μ's能够继续下去
I want you to always be having fun...
希望你们能够一直开心
You are free to come to your own conclusion.
得出什么结论是你的自由哦
I don't get it anymore!
啊 真是莫名其妙
I didn't think it would come to this...
变成这样这种事
Maybe... we should keep going...
果然还是继续下去的话
But...That would mean...
但是 那样的话
Well, It's still the same old story
古老故事情节仍在重复
A fight for love and glory
一场为了爱与荣誉的战斗
This voice!
啊 这个声音是
A case of do or die
去做或是死亡的情节
The world will always welcome lovers
这个世界将永远欢迎有情的恋人们
As time goes by
即使时光荏苒
We meet again!
再次见面了呢
Why?! Why are you here?!
为什么 为什么会在这里啊
That time, you just disappeared!
那个时候突然就消失了
This mic! I have the same one at my house, too!
啊 这个麦克风 上次那个还在我家呢
I've been wanting to say thank you!
我之前想要好好道谢的哟
S-Sorry...
抱歉
Oh yeah! My house is really close by!
啊 对了 我家就在附近
Please come or at least some tea!
至少来喝杯茶吧
I want to give you your mic back, too!
顺便把麦克风还你
What?! Wai-! My stuff!
诶 等下 行李还没拿
It's here. Please come in!
就是这里 请进吧
Right here is fine.
到这里就好了
Maybe next time!
果然还是下次再来吧
Why? After we finally reunited!
为什么 好不容易又相遇了
Did you find your answer?
找到答案了吗
Oh, that time?
那个时候的
Close your eyes...
闭上眼睛
L-Like this?
这样吗
You can fly.
要起飞了哦
Fly?
要飞了
You can fly!
你能飞哦
you can fly whenever you want to!
随时都可以飞翔
Like you did back then!
像那个时候一样
Honoka
穗乃果
It's Eli.
我是绘里
Afterwards, the three of us talked.
在那之后我们三人讨论了一下
About our popularity
我们获得的人气
About how many people listen to our songs...
我们的歌曲被很多的人听着
About how we were asked to help with Love Live...
希望将我们的力量借给LoveLive的事情也是
And we are very happy about that.
我们为此感到很高兴
But...Our answer hasn't changed.
但是我们的答案是不会改变的
We will not be continuing μ's.
μ's 是不会再继续下去的了
We just...
我们果然还是
We're serious about being school idols!
想一直做学园偶像
We love school idols.
我们喜欢学园偶像
For our school
为了学校
For everyone...
为了大家
We students, the nine of us coming together,
聚集了九位同样是学生的同伴
competing with each other...
互相进取
Holding each other's hands...
携手并进
We love school idols!
因为喜欢学园偶像
With the limited time we have,
在有限的时间里
to shine as bright as we can ,
尽最大努力闪耀光辉
Which is what I love about school idols.
因为喜欢学园偶像
I found it... my answer.
找到答案了
I started singing for my school.
我是为了拯救学校开始唱歌的
Started being an idol...
开始做偶像
And met everyone...
然后遇到大家
Aimed for Love Live together...
一起以LoveLive为目标
Ran full force...
全力奔跑着
Toward a goal that
曾经以为那绝对是不可能触及到的
we thought we would never reach...
但是触及到了
And that... It wasn't all coincidence...
那并非是偶然
It was because we were able to focus with all of our might...
因为是尽全力地投入进去了
And...
然后
Because we had so much fun!
也是最开心的事
Girls!
大家
You're really late.
来得太慢了呢
It's been a while.
好久没一起这么集合练习过了
I wanted to practice again!
想着差不多是时候开始练习了
We are still school idols!
我们还是学园偶像
Well, I never cared either way.
嘛 反正我觉得是怎样都好的
Such a pain...When we stick together...
在一起待久了也是挺麻烦的
We understand each other without speaking.
变得什么都不说也能心理神会了
I bet all of our answers are the same, right?
大家的回答一定是一样的吧
It's simply because μ's are school idols.
正因为μ's是学园偶像
No one has any objections, right?
全员无异议 是吧
But the competition at the dome...
但是巨蛋大会的话
We will definitely make it happen!
那个也一定要实现
What do you mean?
怎么回事
We're going to do a concert!
举行演唱会吧
One that will share how wonderful school idols are!
能让大家体会到学院偶像有多么棒的演唱会
A-RISE and μ's aren't the only amazing ones!
厉害的不仅仅是A-RISE和μ's
It's all the school idols!
而是所有的学院偶像
This concert will show that to everyone!
要办一场能让大家体会到这点的演唱会啊
But doesn't that...?
但是那样的话
What do you mean, specifically?
具体该怎么做呢
Actually, I have a great idea!
实际上我有个很厉害的想法
Hey, hey, hey!
呐 呐 呐
well
What?
诶
Are you serious?!
认真的吗
Do we have enough time?!
现在开始能来得及吗
Yeah! Don't you know how much work that'll take?!
你知道这是多困难的事吗
We don't have much time, but...
虽然没什么时间了
If we can pull it off, don't you think it will be fun?!
但是成功了的话不觉得很有趣吗
I like it! I'm on board!
好啊 咱赞成
It sounds fun!
好像很有趣喵
I-If we can do it
要是实 实现了的话
this will be a huge event!
可是不得了的一件事哦
The school idol, Nico-Ni, is ready for anything!
对于学园偶像妮可妮来说不足为惧
That's right! To make the world's most wonderful concert!
对啊 世界上最棒的演唱会
Surely...
确实
It might be the most exciting concert we ever had!
说不定会是至今为止最开心的演唱会
Girls!
大家
Do a concert together?
一起举办演唱会
We, μ's, will split up after all.
我们μ's果然还是准备到此为止了
We haven't told anyone else...
这个除了成员以外其他的人尚且还未告知
But I want us to do this together,
但是想在最后集合各位
and show people how great school idols are!
想向大家传达学园偶像的美妙之处
I see.
原来如此
So if we do a concert that we can enjoy from the bottom of our hearts, then,
要是进行一场我们学园偶像打自心底感到开心的演唱会的话
even if move on,
就算没有了我们
it will definitely cause the dome competition to happen,
巨蛋大会也一定能过顺利进行
right?
是这样吧
Yes!
是的
I didn't expect anything less from you.
真是有你风格的想法
Sounds interesting.
感觉挺有趣
It's not a bad idea to make everybody happy.
能让大家感到开心也不是坏事
We are still scchool idols.
我们现在也还是学园偶像
We will cooperate!
助你一臂之力吧
Thank you very much!
非常感谢
But,
但是
I have a favor to ask.
有个请求
I want to sing a song together.
想让大家唱同一首曲子
Sing a song... together?
让大家唱同一首曲子
That's right!
对的
Not any of our songs,
不是某一个人的曲子
but a song that belongs to all school idols!
而是属于所有学园偶像的曲子
Since we're going to do a concert together,
难得大家一起举行演唱会
we have to use the right song.
也应该有一首与之相称的曲目
We want you to choose that song, as the event champions.
希望由身为大会冠军的你们来创作
What do you think?
觉得如何
That is the one condition for our cooperation.
这就是我们参加演唱会的唯一条件
I want to do it!
我们同意
That sounds really good!
觉得这样非常好
I want to do it!
我也想这样做
But we don't have much time left!
但是没多少时间了哦
It's fine!
没事的
Thanks for the tea!
多谢款待
I'll go tell everyone!
我也去向大家传达
Hot!
好烫
It's amazing!
好厉害
I already received some replies from the e-mail I sent!
发出去的邮件已经有回复了
Really?!
真的!?
But some of them want to discuss it first...
但是里面也有一些说「希望听了具体之后再说」的组合
That's understandable.
确实是
It's difficult to ask them to perform all of a sudden.
一来就让别人出场
They might be confused...
会感到困扰的吧
It might be better to explain it over the phone.
感觉还是打电话好好说明一下比较好
Do you really want to wait around?
这样悠闲着来真的可以吗
We don't have much time left!
时间已经所剩无几了
Well...
这个嘛
Then what should we do?
那怎么办
Let's go meet them!
去见他们吧
Yes, going to meet them is the best thing!
没错 去见她们的话是最…
Huh? What?!
诶
Go meet them?!
去见他们
Seriously?!
认真的吗
Yeah!
恩
Our range may be limited,
虽然只局限于能去的范围内
but if we meet in person,
直接去面谈的话
they will understand our feelings.
心情一定能相通的
But...how?
但是 要怎么做呢
Simple!
很简单哟
Maki-chan!
真姬
Lend us some train fare!
借一下电车费吧
I see!
原来如此
Why are you all looking at me?!
为什么要看这边啦
All right! Let's go!
那么 出发吧
Everyone's waiting for us!
大家在等着我们呢
聴いてもらいたいんだ
想让你听听这首歌
ずっと思い続けて
一直都这样想着
とにかく動きだしてみたら
总而言之开始行动的话
新しい日々のなかで
在崭新的日子里面
少しずつ生まれた未来
一点点诞生的未来
まだ挑戦したいね やれるね
还想挑战而且能做到的吧
みんなで追いかけよう ときめきを
大家一起去追寻那份悸动的心情吧
Future style
会いたいよ その瞬間待っててね
好想见面啊 要等等那个瞬间哦
いつか描いた希望のステージ
不知道何时描绘的希望的舞台
世界中ここにしかない
全世界绝无仅有的这里
Future style
会いたいよ その瞬間待っててね
好想见面啊 要等等那个瞬间哦
今こそぜんぶ叶えたい I wish starting
就是现在想要全部实现 I wish starting
最高の夢をカタチにする時だと
在将最棒的梦想实现的时候
声が 聞こえる!
就能听到声音!
Everyone! Over here, over here!
各位 这边这边
Wait!
等下我
You're too fast!
太快了啦
One, two, three, four!
Five, six, seven, eight!
Wh-What should we do!
怎么办
They're practicing really hard!
她们正在努力练习呢
You should go!
你上吧
M-Me?!
我
You're the president!
你是部长吧
Hello,
大家好 初次见面
I'm Kotori Minima from μ's!
我是μ's的南小鸟
Can we talk with you for a moment?
稍微耽误下可以吗
Wow!
诶
So cute!
好可爱
Wh-What can we do for you?
是什么事呢
If you want us to share a stage with you, let's have a duel!
想要我们站上舞台的话 就决一胜负吧
If you win, we will participate!
赢了的话就给你们出一下场
That's fine! Sounds interesting!
好啊 不是挺有趣的吗
What?!
诶
We'll show you how good we are!
让你们看看认真的μ's吧
What?!
诶
Please come see us!
请多指教
We will be doing a concert!
我们会举行演唱会
Everyone's like us!
大家都和我们一样呢
They're working really hard.
在努力着呢
What should we do?
怎么办呢
We can't just go up and talk to them...
突然搭话感觉有点
This is your time to shine, Rin-chan!
这种时候就是凛呢
What?! Me?!
诶 凛
Here you go!
来 这个
Can we help you?
那个 有什么事情吗
We are the herald of school idols!
吾乃校园偶像的使者
We would like to perform a concert with thou.
欲与汝等共举演出
Um...
嗯
What is that?
那是什么啊
It's a new skill she gained overseas.
在海外学到的新招式哦
How stupid...
这种蠢蠢的东西
They're going to join us!
说是愿意参与进来喵
What?!
诶诶
I got an e-mail!
邮件来了
Not only from Tokyo, but schools from the entire country!
不仅是东京 全国来了好几份
That's amazing!
真是厉害
That's 20 groups already!
这样就已经二十组了喵
Hello!
哈喽
Anju-san!
杏树
We came to help you with making the song!
来帮忙作曲了哦
Here. We brought a gift.
这个 是伴手礼
Oh! What a cute costumes!
啊啦 好可爱的衣裳
Thanks! After Honoka-chan told me, I made them in a hurry!
谢谢 穗乃果通知后赶紧制作的
Both of us have forceful partners.
我们都有个蛮干硬来的伙伴
It's a lot of work!
真是辛苦呢
You need a lot of costumes, right?
需要很多衣裳的吧
I can help!
我来帮忙
Ta-da! I thought of a costume!
锵 我也试着考虑了下服装哟
What do you think?
怎么样
Seriously, it's a lot of work!
真是 辛苦呢
Nice song!
真是好曲子
If you have any ideas, tell me.
有什么点子的话说说看
I'll try to incorporate them.
我加入进去试试
Yeah...
是呢
Well... how about this?
那么 这样的怎么样
What are you doing?
你在做什么
N-Nothing!
没 没什么
Maki-chan, huh?
原来是真姬呀
Hmph!
哼
I told you, it's nothing!
都说了没什么了
Anyways, aren't we singing the song we listened to last time? The one Maki wrote?
比起这个 不是要唱之前听过的真姬的歌吗
They look like they're getting along, making new songs...
关系很好的样子 而且似乎又在做新的曲子
I told her the same thing, but...She said that song is for the nine members of μ's to sing...
咱也说过了 但是她说因为那是想让μ's九个人来演唱的歌曲
What's up with that?
什么啊那是
These are posts gathered from the whole country.
这是来自全国的话语
There's this many?!
原来有那么多吗
We're going to select from this...?
从这里面挑选
It's filled with everyone's thoughts.We're going to do it!
充满大家的情感 要上了
Um, all right, everyone! Hello!
大家好
Thank you so much for coming today!
十分感谢大家今天能够聚集在这里
This concert...It's different from the competition It's a concert handmade by everyone!
这场演唱会和大会不同 是大家一起自己制作的演唱会
We make one stage with our own hands!
用自己的手制作舞台
We call out to the people on our own two feet!
用自己的脚步来呼唤许多的人
With our own strength, let's lead this concert to success!
用自己的力量来让这场演唱会走向成功吧
Sis!
姐姐
You're gonna help us?!
愿意来帮忙吗
Yup! Of course!
嗯 当然
But, we're not real school idols yet!
但是我们还不是学园偶像
Can we still participate?!
参与进来也没问题吗
YES, YOU CAN!
没关系
We have this, you know...
有这个哦
We will be having a concert tomorrow!
明天要举办演唱会
With a ton of performers!
这次是全员参加的演唱会
Let's all sing together!
大家来一起歌唱吧
Please come!
请多指教
Welcome!
欢迎光临
We have a yummy menu that all the school idols came up with!
有学园偶像想出来的美味菜品哦
Um...
那个
It's written here...
写在这里的
Something about a white rice smoothie... What is that?
白米冰沙是什么
Uh... Well, that's...
那个是
Please come!
请多指教
Please participate!
大家请参与进来
Thank you very much!
谢谢
Please come to our concert, okay?
演唱会也请一定来参加
Is this okay?
这样可以吗
A little more to the right!
再稍微右边点
Yahoo, everyone! Are you cutting loose?!
呀吼 大家有好好的嗨起来吗
Tomorrow, school idols nationwide are coming together to perform a special concert!
没想到明天全国的学园偶像要发表特别演唱会
How exciting! How exciting!
真令人期待 真是令人期待呢
Honoka! Good luck!
穗乃果 加油
Good luck!
加油
Thank you!
谢谢
Please come to our concert, okay?!
大家也要一起参加演唱会哦
We're doing a concert!
要举办演唱会
Please come!
请大家一起参加
It is done.
完成了
Are you seriously going to drape this?
这个是真打算挂起来么
Ready!
一 二
We did it!
完成了
It's a little crooked in some places...
虽然还有些地方做的很粗糙
It adds flavor, doesn't it?
这不也很有味吗
Everyone will be on a stage we made together...
在自己制作的舞台上大家一起
I'm so pumped!
真是令人激动喵
It makes you wanna dance, huh?
总感觉想要跳起舞来了呢
What are you talking about?
在说什么啊
Tomorrow is the real deal!
正式的在明天
Do you wanna just practice?
但是要不来练习吧
Right now?
现在开始吗
It's already the afternoon.
都已经傍晚了
A-RISE can't do it on short notice--
就算是A-RISE这样突然的
I don't mind.
倒是没有什么问题
Sounds good!
不错呢
All right!
好
Let's all practice for the end!
那么最后大家来练习吧
Yeah!- All right! Let's do this!
好 要上了
We're gonna follow A-RISE and μ's!
跟着A-RISE和μ's上了
I'm gonna work hard!
要加油了
Me, too!
就算是我
Honoka?
穗乃果
Hey, everyone...
呐 大家
There's something we need to tell you all.
我们 有不得不告诉大家的事情
"We... definitely..." "we 're serious about being school idols!"
我们果然还是必须要作为一名校园偶像才行
Um!
那个
We...
我们
We, μ's...
我们μ's决定了
After this concert, have decided to end all further activities.
在这场演唱会后结束活动
We love school idols.
我们喜欢学园偶像
We sang for our school,
为了学校歌唱
and we held each other's hands.
为了大家歌唱
competed with one another
相互竞争
and we held each other's hands.
然后互相牵手
In this limited time, to work so hard to shine
最喜欢在这被限定了的时间里
is what we love about school idols!
尽力发光的学园偶像了
μ's wants to cherish this feeling...
μ's想要珍视这一份感情
We talked about it together, and that is what we decided.
和大家商量之后做出了这样的决定
Sis...
姐姐
But, Love Live will keep growing...
但是LoveLive会更加广泛的传播开来
I want to bring school idols that shine,
想要将大家的 学园偶像的美好
and everything wonderful about them, to as many people as we can!
和今后也会一直闪耀下去的光芒传达给更多的人
If we join our powers together,
只要将我们的力量合为一体
hopefully, from now on, Love Live will continue to grow enormously!
这之后LoveLive也一定能广泛的传播开来
No way...
怎么会
That's why... we will not sing an ending song!
所以 明天不会唱完结的歌
We must sing for all the school idols and for those who support school idols!
和我们一起 为了学园偶像和支持着学园偶像的大家歌唱吧
Having our thoughts together...With evertone as one!There we go.
与情感共融为一的大家一起
There we go.
好了
Oh! Good morning!
啊 早上好
Hello!
你好
All right!
好
Morning, Honoka-chan!
早上好 穗乃果
Morning!
早上好
Let's Go!
走吧
Did you get a good night's sleep?
好好睡了吗
Yup! Right on!
嗯 妥妥的
I'm glad the weather lit up!
天空也正好放晴了
Seriously! It's gonna be a good concert!
确实 感觉会成为一场好演唱会
But... isn't it weird?
但是 真是不可思议
When Love Live was over, I thought that was it...
LoveLive结束的时候感觉所有的事情已经做完了
There was nothing more we could do...
还没做的事情已经一件也没有了
Me, too.
我也是
I never thought we would go on a plane.
没想到会坐上飞机
But it was a lot of fun!
但是 真是很开心呢
Yeah!
嗯
Oh! Hey!
啊 这里
Morning!
早上好
You girls are early!
大家真是早呢
We spent the night at Kayo-chin's place last night!
昨天住在花阳亲家里了
Because someone was so nervous, she couldn't sleep...
因为有人说太紧张会睡不着
N-Not true!
才 才不是
M-Mama said I could go, so...
因为妈妈说没关系所以
Mama?
妈妈
Maki-chan! Good luck!
真姬 加油
I'm going to gather all the moms and participate in the concert!
大家的妈妈也会集合起来一起参加演唱会
The moms, too?!
妈妈们也
Is that a "Mama Live"?
那么是妈妈Live
Gosh! I told her not to come!
真是的都说不要来了
Good thing it's going to be so lively!
变得热热闹闹的不是挺好的嘛
Okay, let's go!
那么走吧
Good morning!
早上好
Let's do our best!
卯足干劲上吧
Looks like nobody was late.
好像没有人迟到
Well, we still don't know about one of us...
还有一个人不知道
No. She's probably the first one there, waiting for us.
不 一定比谁都早的在等着呢
Oh! Here's Nico-chan!
啊 找到妮可了
You're late!
太慢了
Were you here all by yourself, Nico-chan?
妮可 一直一个人吗
You're too anxious!
你也太有干劲了
So what?!It's the day of the concert!
又没什么 今天是演唱会当天
Hmph!
哼
Well, now all of μ's is here!
那么 这样μ's就全员到齐了
Good thing you told them all yesterday...About us.
昨天说出来了真好呢 我们的事情
Yeah.
嗯
That's true.
是呢
I feel the same way.
我也这样想
Gosh, you just had to say it out of nowhere, Honoka-chan.
真是的 都因为穗乃果突然就说出来了
I'm sorry.
不好意思
But now, there is nothing to be worried or hesitant about...
但是这样就没有任何迷惑和踌躇的事情了
Right?
对吧
We are school idols till the very end.
我们到最后都是学园偶像
For the future Love Live, let's give it our all!
为了未来的LoveLive使出全力吧
Eli-chan...
绘里
Yeah!
嗯
All right! I'll race you to UTX!
那么 到UTX为止赛跑吧
The loser buys everyone juice!
输了的人请大家喝果汁
Huh?
诶
No fair, you got a head start! Meow!
抢先太狡猾了喵
I won't lose!
我不会输哦
"I can fly now..."
能够跨越过去
"I can fly whenever!"
什么时候都能越过去
"Like I did back then!"
就像那个时候一样
Honoka!
穗乃果
What is...?
这是
As you can see...
和你看到的一样
When they heard your words...
听到了你们的呼声
We were able to gather all these people.
聚集到了那么多的人
This many...
这么多
Now, the time has come!
来吧 时间到了
Unlike the competition, we are not rivals right now.
和大会不同 现在不是对手
We are one!
我们共为一体
WE ARE SCHOOL IDOLS!
我们是学园偶像
Yeah!
嗯
Everyone! Thank you for coming here today!
大家 今天感谢大家聚集起来
It's almost showtime!
终于要正式开始了
We can probably go anywhere we want right now!
现在的我们的话一定无论什么都没问题
We can achieve any dream!
不管什么梦想都能实现
Let's tell them!
传达吧
How amazing school idols really are!
学园偶像的美好
楽しいねこんな夢
这样的梦真是开心
えがおで喜び歌おうよ
带着笑容来歌唱喜悦
それが始まりの合図
这是开始的暗号
一歩ずつ君から 一歩ずつ僕から
从你开始一步一步 从我开始一步一步
どこかへ行きたい心のステップ
想要去哪的心灵的舞步
受けとめてあげるここで
我会在这里接纳全部
最初は少しためらっても
虽然最初有一些犹豫
受けとめる場所があるって
但是我想更多的让你
もっともっと知ってほしくなるよ…なるよ!
明白有能够接纳的地方…的地方!
SUNNY DAY SONG
SUNNY DAY SONG 高く跳びあがれ
SUNNY DAY SONG 高高的跳跃吧
どんなことも乗り越えられる気がするよ
感觉任何事情都能这样的跨越过去
SUNNY DAY SONG
SUNNY DAY SONG 口ずさむ時は
SUNNY DAY SONG 唱起歌的时候
明日への期待がふくらんでいい気持ち
就会沉浸在对明日的期待的舒适感觉里
SUNNY DAY Wow! Sun power!
SUNNY DAY Wow! Sun power
SUNNY DAY Wow! Song power!
元気でるこんな夢
让人充满精神的这样的梦
あれこれみんなで語ろうよ
大家一起说着这样那样的事
それは繋がりのサイン
这就是联系大家的标识
二歩目はしっかりと 三歩目は大胆に
第二步要脚踏实地 第三步要大胆的
おそれず行けそうな予感でダンス
毫无畏惧带着能行预感的舞蹈
自分から手を伸ばしたら
自己来伸出手的话
もっともっと面白くなるよ…なるよ!
一定会变的更有趣的……更有趣的!
SUNNY DAY LIFE
SUNNY DAY LIFE 輝きになろう
SUNNY DAY LIFE 成为光芒吧
なんて言える今の気分を分け合えば
如果能够互相分享现在的心情的话
SUNNY DAY LIFE
SUNNY DAY LIFE 君も踊り出す
SUNNY DAY LIFE 你也一起起舞
幸せの予感に包まれ なんでもできそうさ
被幸福的预感笼廓着感觉什么都能做到
SUNNY DAY LIFE
SUNNY DAY LIFE 輝きになろう
なんて言える今の気分を分け合えば
如果能够互相分享现在的心情的话
SUNNY DAY LIFE
SUNNY DAY LIFE 君も踊り出す Ah!
SUNNY DAY LIFE 你也一起起舞…Ah!
SUNNY DAY SONG
SUNNY DAY SONG 高く跳びあがれ
SUNNY DAY SONG 高高的跳跃吧
どんなことも乗り越えられる気がするよ
感觉任何事情都能这样的跨越过去
SUNNY DAY SONG
SUNNY DAY SONG 口ずさむ時は
SUNNY DAY SONG 唱起歌的时候
明日への期待がふくらんでいい気持ち
就会沉浸在对明日的期待的舒适感觉里
SUNNY DAY Wow! Sun power!
SUNNY DAY Wow! Song power!
(歌うよ)
(歌唱吧)
SUNNY DAY Wow! Sun power!
(こんな夢)
(这样的梦)
SUNNY DAY Wow! Song power!
Ready?
注意要拍了哟
Okay!
好
Both of you are heavy!
两个人太重了
Hey, Nico! Don't push me!
真是的 妮可不要推啊
Yeah!
是啊
Don't worry, don't worry!
不要在意不要在意
Stop messing around, you guys!
大家不要吵闹
All right, everyone!Let's do the thing we practiced!
那么大家 练习过的那个
Let's go!
要上了
Ready!
一 二
LOVELIVE!
Morning!
早上好
You're late!
太慢了哦
Sorry!
抱歉
So first we explain to the first years what kind of activities we do.
听好了 首先要向一年级的说明我们的活动内容
If they're interested, we have them come to our concert.
如果有兴趣的话下次就让她们参加演唱会
Got it! Leave it to me!
没问题 交给我
Can I...?
真的吗
To all the new students,
新生的大家
congratulations on your acceptance to our school.
恭喜入学
From today onwards, you are all members of Otonokizaka High.
今天开始大家就是这音乃木坂的一员
From this moment on, please have a fun and fulfilling school life.
这之后的学园生活请一定充实快乐的度过
Idol Research Department
偶像研究部
The school idols
学园偶像
μ's
were born from this very Otonokizaka High.
是在这所音乃木坂学园诞生的
From saving the school from shutting down,
将学校从废校危机中拯救出来
until winning the competition...
到大会中优胜为止
We inherited those memories,
我们将这份感情继承下来
and have been carrying out the activities till now.
展开活动至今
With μ's as the center,the power of school idols
因为μ's做为中心的学园偶像的力量
guaranteed that Love Live would always happen at the Akiba Dome
LoveLive终于能够举办巨蛋大会
And omce more, with the dome competition as our goal, the preliminaries have begun.
今年也以巨蛋为目标展开了预赛
And... as for μ's and their final concert...
还有 μ's最后的演唱会是
All right! Let's go!
那么 要上了
One!
一
Two!
二
Three!
三
Four!
四
Five!
五
Six!
六
Seven!
七
Eight!
八
Nine!
九
μ's
Music!
Music
START!
START
Ah! ほのかな予感から始まり
Ah!从微小的预感开始
Ah! 希望が星空駈けて
Ah! 希望奔驰在星空中
花を咲かせるにっこリ笑顔は
让花朵绽开的笑容
ずっと同じさ 友情の笑顔
是永远不变的友情的笑容
忘れない いつまでも忘れない
不会忘记 无论何时都不会忘记
こんなにも心がひとつになる
这样的大家的心聚集到一起
世界を見つけた喜びともに歌おう
与发现世界的喜悦
最後まで 僕たちはひとつ
歌唱到最后 我们是一起的
小鳥の翼がついに大きくなって
小鸟的翅膀终于变丰满
旅立ちの日だよ
是旅途开始的日子了
遠くへと広がる海の色暖かく
广阔的大海的颜色如此温暖
夢の中で描いた絵のようなんだ
就像梦中描绘的那个样子
切なくて時をまきもどしてみるかい?
悲伤的时候不试着将时间倒转回去?
No no no ... いまが最高!
No no no 现在就最棒!
みんなと出会えたこと嬉しくて
能够和大家相遇
離れたくないよ本当だよ
高兴的让我不想分开是真的哦
涙はいらない このまま踊ろう
不要眼泪 就这样舞动
手を振ってもっと振って
挥手吧更用力的挥手吧
光を追いかけてきた僕たちだから
因为追逐的光芒到来的我们
さよならは言わない
不会说再见
また会おう 呼んでくれるかい?
会再次呼唤我相见吗?
僕たちのこと
关于我们的事情
素敵だった未来に繋がった夢 夢の未来
与美好的未来紧紧联系着的梦 梦与未来
君と僕のLIVE&LIFE
你与我的LIVE&LIFE
小鳥の翼がついに大きくなって
小鸟的翅膀终于变丰满
旅立ちの日だよ
是旅途开始的日子了
遠くへと広がる海の色暖かく
广阔的大海的颜色如此温暖
夢の中で描いた絵のようなんだ
就像梦中描绘的那个样子
切なくて時をまきもどしてみるかい?
悲伤的时候不试着将时间倒转回去?
No no no いまが最高!
No no no 现在就最棒!
だってだって、いまが最高!
因为因为 现在就是最棒!
Ah! ほのかな予感から始まり
AH!从微小的预感开始
Ah! 光を追いかけてきたんだよ…
Ah! 因为追逐的光芒到来…